Hey guys, so I welcome to another video.
So this is one of interesting thing we are going to see one of a tool called TDSS killer
that was the tool is developed by the test security, so that tool was used to remove
the root kits and other malware from the machine.
But our thing is what we are going to do, we are going to remove the bin different, okay,
the defender service from the machine, okay.
So if you see this tool, it was built by the casper sky.
Even you can also download it in soft turning.
If you check in the bleating computer, so it was saying, it will remove the root kits, okay.
So some of the threat factors, they are, they are even abusing this tool to TDSS killer
might, yeah, some of the threat factors even, even using this tool are to remove the
defender or remove the EDR services from our endpoints, okay.
So here you can find logbit 3.0, they have used the TDSS killer to EDR evasion.
So this is one of something which we can do to evade from different mechanism, okay.
So the main objective of the tool is designed to kill root kits, but what threat factors
often you engineer is doing, so they are abusing this tool to kill the defense mechanism,
okay.
If the tool is thing, the defense, when defender, windows, defenders, root kits and it will
kill the service, okay.
Let us see, you can see an impaired defense, the transmission in mitre also.
So if you see the documentation here, so we can have multiple options, but we are going
to use this option, delete the specific service, only if you sure service should be removed.
Okay.
So in my machine, I already have a TDS killer that get downloaded and I given a link
how to even download the TDS killer, okay.
So let me show you something here, TDS killer, DCSPC.
So if you given this, I will give some information how to use this tool.
So our option is here, so to DCSST to service name and delete the service.
So now let me search for the SE query when different, let me search for the service, the
when different was running or not.
So now I can see the when different was running in our machine.
So it's Windows Defender service, so we can use TDS killer to start this service, okay.
TDS killer - DCSPC, and we need to see the service name in the front.
So now it was initializing the process and getting some measures and now it was seeing
it necessary to remove the reboot for your competition.
So if I do the details, so you can see it will be deleted after the reboot, the key has
been deleted once if I reboot my machine.
So think of it, how cool the threat factors will be doing this stuff, okay.
They are more and more advanced, they are abusing the manual removal tool and they are
killing the defense mechanism service, okay.
So one time be phased the incident active incident like attacker, attack one of them organization
with the tool, okay.
So I was investigating the incident and I can see one thing, the TDS killer, the hash of
the hash file matching to a casper's case, so I was thinking what was going, why it was
killing Defender, why it was killing our EDR, EDR services.
Then I just realized something going on because if you install a new Antiverse program,
it will kill some of the current triggers of the current services and it will do something,
okay.
The user is studying the TDS killer, root kit maneuver, that was a problem, okay.
So the assumption I made that was completely wrong, so that's new, that's the new, the
threat factor used, that's the first time the threat factor used the TDS killer to
degrade the service, okay.
So we phased active incidents and finally the ransomware has been arrived, so my mistake,
there, I just assumed this is legitimate activity from the user.
So when you doing some kind of blue teaming based investigation or foreign success, you
need to be aware about this root kit remover tools, not only the TDS killer, we have other
root kit remover tools also, so that will be enough to delete the services from the
information, even the legitimate services, like wind defenders, EDR services, even Palo Alto,
Kotx area, Cloud Sega or anything, that can, that's, that's capable to boot, okay.
So please, we more focus on when you're investigating.
So that's all about the video, I hope you have enjoyed this video, we'll hope of and we'll
connect you guys in the next video, bye.